Guide to the Artmakers Records MSS.564
Fales Library and Special Collections
Artmakers Records
1964-2019
1972-2018
Fales Library and Special Collections
Artmakers Inc.
Weissman, Jane
MSS.564
20.94 Linear Feet in 11 manuscript boxes, 2 half manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, 5 small flat boxes, 9 oversized flat boxes, 17 flat-file folders, 2 rolled storage boxes, 6 folders in 3 shared oversized flat boxes, and 29 computer disks in 8 shared card boxes and 1 shared half manuscript box
30.3 Gigabytes in 5474 computer files
4 VHS
2 audiocassettes
Artmakers Inc. is a community mural organization that develops and creates politically-oriented public art relevant to the lives and concerns of the neighborhoods in which the murals are. Artmakers was established in 1983 and has created over 50 murals nationally and internationally, with a strong focus on New York City. The group is artist-run, and works in collaboration with many community organizations. This collection consists of materials in paper and electronic format documenting the activities and creative works of the Artmakers Inc. collective from the 1980s to the 2010s. Materials in this collection include correspondence, project documentation, photographs, books and other publications, flyers and other ephemera, artist portfolios, research files, and process documentation for murals and other works.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Jane Weissman in November 2018 and February 2019; the accession numbers associated with these gifts are 2018.131 and 2019.032.
Arrangement
The collection has been arranged into two series, chronologically within each one. The series arrangement is as follows:
Series I. Administration
Series II. Murals, Exhibitions, and Projects
Historical Note
Artmakers Inc. is a community mural organization that develops and creates politically-oriented public art relevant to the lives and concerns of the neighborhoods in which the murals are located. Artmakers was established in 1983 and has created over 50 murals nationally and internationally, the majority of which are in New York City. The group is artist-run, and works in collaboration with many community organizations, including block associations, schools, community gardens, homeless shelters, health care facilities, and other artist groups, to develop mural projects. The organization also offers an apprenticeship program for youth to build their artistic abilities and professional skills.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact Fales Library with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of materials in paper and electronic format documenting the activities and creative works of the Artmakers Inc. collective from the 1980s to the late 2010s. Also included are materials from Cityarts Workshop (later, Cityarts, Inc.), an organization that existed prior to, and concurrently with, the founding of Artmakers and shared many of its artists. Materials in this collection include correspondence; project documentation such as preparatory drawings and paintings; books and other publications; flyers and other ephemera; artist portfolios; research files; documentaries; and interviews. Artists prominently documented in this collection include Eva Cockcroft, Janet Braun-Reinitz, and Camille Perrottet. Topics and themes include women's rights, community organizing, the African diaspora, and New York City neighborhoods. This collection also includes materials produced during the writing and publishing of On the Wall: Four Decades of Community Murals in New York City, a history of community murals in New York City.
Art -- Political aspects.; Mural painting and decoration -- United States.; street art; Public art spaces.; Politics in art.; Weissman, Jane; Braun-Reinitz, Janet; Cockcroft, Eva Sperling; Perrottet, Camille; Weissman, Jane
- Series I. Administration, 1972-2019; 3.60 Linear Feet in 4 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, 1 small flat box, and 1 oversized flat box; 3 VHS; 2 audiocassette; 1.77 Gigabytes in 378 computer files
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of administrative materials created by Artmakers in the course of its daily operations. Also included are administrative materials from Cityarts Workshop, mostly from the time before Artmakers was formed and during its early years. Materials include historical documents (e.g., articles of incorporation), general correspondence, grant proposals, financial documents, artists' files (if they participated with the group), permissions, conference submissions and proposals, and lecture notes/other presentation materials (e.g., PowerPoints). Artists' files, mostly of artists who collaborated with Artmakers, include slides, biographies, art reviews, writing, and exhibition postcards, mostly for events not sponsored by Artmakers but related to murals and/or community art. Additionally, there are audiotapes and a videotape of Eva Cockcroft's memorial service, an interview with Jane Weissman about the history of murals in New York City, and flyers and brochures of Social and Public Art Resource Center (SPARC), a similar organziation to Artmakers, located in Los Angeles, California.
  - Cityarts Workshop, 1972-1990
    - Goals, Staff Lists, Press, Artist Guidelines, and Budgets, 1972-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - The Creative Process: A Traveling Exhibition of Selected Public Art Projects Realized by Cityarts, Inc., 1968-1990 Catalog (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Artmakers, 1983-2019
    - Brochures, Correspondence, Lecture Announcements, and Proposals, 1983-2018 (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
    - Scrapbook, 1985-1989 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Map of Murals Co-Sponsored by United Community Centers (UCC), circa 1996 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Electronic Records, 2003-2019; FA_MSS_564_ER_1
  - Artist Files, 1978-2018
    - Asher, Ricki, 1984-2006 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Bender, Leslie, 1982-2018
      - Exhibition Announcements, Postcards, and Press, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Electronic Records, 2018; FA_MSS_564_ER_2
    - Bimka, Therese, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Bloomer, Ken, circa 1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Braun-Reinitz, Janet, 1987-2018; FA_MSS_564_ER_3
      - Exhibition Announcements, Postcards, and Press, 1987-2001 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Electronic Records, 2002-2018; FA_MSS_564_ER_3
    - Braun-Reinitz, Janet and Rochelle Shicoff, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Cockcroft, Eva, 1972-2008
      - Exhibition Announcements, Postcards, Press, Photographs, and Writing, 1972-2000 (Box 2, Folder 1-5, Box 3, Folder 1-3, Box 15, Folder 3, Box 20)
      - Electronic Records, 2003-2008; FA_MSS_564_ER_4
    - Cosin, Catherine, 1988-2018
      - Exhibition Postcards and Press, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Electronic Records, 2018; FA_MSS_564_ER_5
    - Dominguez, Maria, 1984-2017 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Jemisin, Noah, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Joseph, Cliff, 2018
      - Drawings and Exhibition Press, 2018 (Box 3, Folder 7, Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Electronic Records, 2018; FA_MSS_564_ER_6
    - Kuo, Nina, circa 1988 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Lady Pink, 2005-2018 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Michals, Robin, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Ortega, Susan Ackoff, 2016-2017; FA_MSS_564_ER_7
    - Perrottet, Camille, circa 1978-2019
      - Exhibition Photographs, Postcards, and Press, circa 1978-1985 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Electronic Records, 2008-2019; FA_MSS_564_ER_8
    - Pfister, Kristi, 1986-2005 (Box 3, Folder 12, Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Reed, Kristin, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Romero, Rachael L., 1989-2018
      - Exhibition Press and Postcards, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Electronic Records, 2018; FA_MSS_564_ER_9
    - Stephenson, Joe, 1979-1987
      - Exhibition Photographs, Press, and Postcards, 1979-1987 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Electronic Records, FA_MSS_564_ER_10
    - Talbot, Nina, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Togut, Susan, 1990-1996
      - Exhibition Postcards and Press, 1990-1996 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Electronic Records, FA_MSS_564_ER_11
    - Multiple Artists, 1982-1998
      - Exhibition Announcements, Photographs, and Press, 1982-1989 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
      - "Community Murals: Eva Cockcroft and Friends" -- by Daniel del Solar, November 1998 (Box 14, Vhs 564.0003)
      - Electronic Records, FA_MSS_564_ER_12
    - Unidentified Drawings, undated (Box 4, Folder 3, Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Artists Affiliated with Operation GreenThumb, 1986-2005
      - Exhibition Photographs, Announcements, and Press, 1986-2005 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Electronic Records, FA_MSS_564_ER_13
    - Artists Unaffiliated with Artmakers, 1980-1989
      - Press, Biography, and Slides, 1980-1987 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - "The Pathfinder Mural Project for a World Without Borders" -- by Eric Heimbold, 1989 (Box 14, Vhs 564.0005)
      - Electronic Records, FA_MSS_564_ER_14
  - Social and Public Art Resource Center (SPARC) -- Venice, CA, circa 1979-1998 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Eva Cockcroft Memorial Service, May 2, 1999
    - Audio Recording (Box 14, Audiocassette 564.0001)
    - Audio Recording (Box 14, Audiocassette 564.0002)
    - Video Recording (Box 14, Vhs 564.0006)
  - Everything Is Broken with Jim Lynch -- Audio Interview with Jane Weissman, December 8, 2009; FA_MSS_564_ER_32
- Series II. Murals, Exhibitions, and Projects, 1964-2018; 14.33 Linear Feet in 8 manuscript boxes, 3 half manuscript boxes, 5 small flat boxes, 8 oversized flat boxes, 2 rolled storage boxes, 16 flat file folders, and 6 folders in 3 oversized boxes; 1 VHS; 28.6 Gigabytes in 5096 computer files
  This series contains production-related materials for each mural, exhibition, or project supported by Artmakers, either independently or in collaboration with other organizations (such as Operation Greenthumb and United Community Centers). Documentation about murals sponsored by Cityarts Workshop and painted by artists who collaborated with Artmakers are included here. All of the materials reflect the organization's commitment to involving the community in the creation of its murals. Materials, in paper and electronic formats, include correspondence, photographs, preparatory drawings and paintings, press releases, postcards, exhibition programs, painting schedules, and budgets. Materials related to the publication of On the Wall: Four Decades of Community Murals in New York City include a prospectus, grant application, background/research materials, correspondence with the publisher, press clippings, and photographs.
  - Cityarts Workshop/Cityarts, Inc., 1980-2003
    - Cockcroft, Eva -- City and Country: Greenmarket Mural, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Stephenson, Joe -- Various Murals, 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Bender, Leslie -- PS 82's Come from the World, Give to the World, 1982 (Box Shared Fales 117, Folder 9, Box Shared Fales 155, Folder 1, Flat-file-folder 4)
    - Cockcroft, Eva -- The Flushing Mural, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 9, Flat-file-folder 1)
    - Cockcroft, Eva -- Puerto Rico: Feasts, Landscape, and Culture -- Borinquen Plaza Senior Citizen Center, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 10, Flat-file-folder 5 left)
    - Ortega, Susan Ackoff -- We Shall Live and Build Together, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 7, Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Bender, Leslie -- Dungeons and Dragons, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 1, Flat-file-folder 2)
    - Bender, Leslie -- Hebrew Educational Society Project, 1982-1983 (Box 25, Box 27, Folder 1-7, Flat-file-folder 9 Left, Flat-file-folder 8 Left)
    - Ortega, Susan Ackoff -- Through the Golden Years, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Stephenson, Joe -- St. Albans Greatest Hits -- Restoration, 1983-1988 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Braun-Reinitz, Janet -- Home Run, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Stephenson, Joe -- St. Albans Greatest Hits Restoration and St. Albans Greatest: They All Lived Here, 2001-2003 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Cockcroft, Eva -- Unidentified School Project Drawings, undated (Flat-file-folder 3)
  - Artists Call Against US Intervention in Central America -- Poster, 1984 (Flat-file-folder 3)
  - Various Artists -- Ballooning, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Stephenson, Joe -- Grosvenor House Mural -- Co-Sponsored by Artmakers, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Cockcroft, Eva (Project Director) -- La Lucha Continua: The Struggle Continues, 1984-1988
    - Correspondence, Press, Call for Proposals, and Budget, 1984-1988 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Drawings, circa 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 8, Box 15, Flat-file-folder 2)
    - Negatives and Contact Sheets, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Photographs, circa 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 10-11, Box 15, Folder 9, Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Posters, 1985-1986 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Slides, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Video Recording -- "La Lucha Continua" -- First Edit, circa 1985-1986 (Box 14, Vhs 564.0004)
    - La Lucha Continua: The Struggle Continues -- Film by John Hunt, 1985; FA_MSS_564_ER_33
    - Electronic Records, FA_MSS_564_ER_15
  - Artists for Nicaragua: A Benefit Exhibition, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Reed, Kristin and Robin Michals -- The Enchanted Garden Mural -- Co-Sponsored by Artmakers, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Cockcroft, Eva (Project Director) -- Push Crack Back, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Stephenson, Joe -- East New York Project/Bicor Building -- Co-Sponsored by Artmakers, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Cockcroft, Eva -- Homage to Seurat: La Grande Jatte in Harlem -- Collaboration with Operation GreenThumb's Artists in the Gardens Program, 1986-1987
    - Correspondence, Press, and Photographs, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Preparatory Drawings, circa 1986 (Box 15, Folder 10, Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Jemisin, Noah -- 174th Street Mural, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Various Artists -- Stars of the Bronx, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 7, Folder 14)
  - Artists Speak to the Issues: Election 1988 -- Co-Sponsored by Artmakers and Bronx River Art Center (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Reed, Kristin (Project Director) -- The Changing Face of Soho, 1988-1990
    - Correspondence and Press, 1988-1990 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Drawings, Plans, and Blueprint, 1964-1988 (Box 6, Folder 10, Box 15, Folder 11, Box 20, Folder 7, Box 22, Folder 4, Box 23, Flat-file-folder 6 Left)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Rolled items in box 23 must be reviewed by a conservator prior to use.
    - Photographs, circa 1988 (Box 6, Folder 11-12)
    - Negatives and Slides, circa 1988 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Electronic Records, FA_MSS_564_ER_16
  - Progressive Propaganda: Artmakers Address the Issues, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Braun-Reinitz, Janet -- A Future for Every Child -- Collaboration with UCC, 1989
    - Correspondence, Photographs, Slides, and Press, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Preparatory Drawings, circa 1989 (Flat-file-folder 5 left)
  - Cosin, Catherine (Project Director) -- Don't Drink and Drive, 1989-1990
    - Correspondence, Research Material, and Press, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 1, Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Drawings, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 2, Box 20, Folder 8, Flat-file-folder 5 left)
    - Slides, Negatives, and Photographs, circa 1989 (Box 7, Folder 3, Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Braun-Reinitz, Janet -- The Saints/Yankees Mural -- Co-Sponsored by Artmakers and Community Arts St. Helens, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Cockcroft, Eva and Kristin Reed -- The Political Landscape Mural and Exhibition -- Co-Sponsored by Artmakers and Hillwood Art Museum, Long Island University, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 5, Flat-file-folder 5 left)
  - Togut, Susan -- Propagation -- Co-Sponsored by Artmakers and Operation GreenThumb's Artists in the Gardens Program, 1988-1996
    - Archival Reproductions of Four Simulated Stained Glass Panels, 1990-1996 (Box Shared Fales 117, Folder 5-6)
    - Maquette, 1988 (Box 26)
  - Multiple Artists -- Venceremos, 1991
    - Exhibition Postcards and Photographs, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Electronic Records, FA_MSS_564_ER_17
  - Braun-Reinitz, Janet -- By the Beautiful Sea -- Collaboration with UCC, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Braun-Reinitz, Janet -- Mantis Mural and Mantis Too -- Co-Sponsored by Artmakers and Operation GreenThumb's Artists in the Gardens Program, 1991-1996
    - Photographs, Correspondence, and Press, 1991-1996 (Box 7, Folder 8, Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Preparatory Paintings, circa 1991 (Box 22, Folder 6, Flat-file-folder 7 Left)
  - Braun-Reinitz, Janet -- Freedom Train: A Multiracial Journey -- Collaboration with UCC, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Multiple Artists -- The Gardens of the Animals -- Co-Sponsored by Artmakers and Auburn Shelter, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Braun-Reinitz, Janet and Rochelle Shicoff -- East New York Women's Wall -- Collaboration with UCC, 1993-1995 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Braun-Reinitz, Janet -- Dream on Jerome -- Collaboration with UCC, 1993-1996 (Box 7, Folder 12, Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Braun-Reinitz, Janet -- The Art of Healing -- Collaboration with UCC, 1993-1999 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Dowling, Wong -- We're Still Waiting -- Collaboration with UCC, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Shicoff, Rochelle and Janet Braun-Reinitz -- Choices: The Pensacola Mural -- Co-Sponsored by Artmakers, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Shicoff, Rochelle and Janet Braun-Reinitz -- Bringing Health to Our Communities -- Co-Sponsored by Artmakers and Planned Parenthood of New York City, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Braun-Reinitz, Janet -- No Violence/Violencia No -- Collaboration with UCC, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Unidentified Events and Murals -- Photographs, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Multiple Artists -- The Aldo Cycle -- Co-Sponsored by Artmakers and Operation GreenThumb's Artists in the Gardens Program, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Braun-Reinitz, Janet -- Signs and Symbols: From Mali, West Africa, to Brooklyn, New York -- Collaboration with UCC, 1996
    - Drawings, Stencils, and Press, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Photographs, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 9, Box Shared Fales 110, Folder 8)
  - Shicoff, Rochelle and Janet Braun-Reinitz -- Pride -- Co-Sponsored by Artmakers, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Braun-Reinitz, Janet -- As Time Goes By -- Collaboration with UCC, 1997
    - Photographs and Press, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Preparatory Drawings and Paintings, 1997 (Flat-file-folder 1)
  - Dowling, Wong, Janet Braun-Reinitz, and Rochelle Shicoff -- That's True! -- Collaboration with UCC, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Shicoff, Rochelle and Janet Braun-Reinitz -- Imagine -- Collaboration with UCC, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Braun-Reinitz, Janet -- Celebrating 25 Years of Struggle -- Collaboration with UCC, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Braun-Reinitz, Janet -- Pea Pods and Butterfiles -- Collaboration with UCC, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Braun-Reinitz, Janet (Designer/Lead Artist) -- Homage to Eva: La Lucha Continua, 2002-2008
    - Postcards, Programs, and Notes, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Drawings, circa 2002 (Box 9, Folder 2, Box 20, Folder 9, Flat-file-folder 1)
    - Photographs, 2002-2008 (Box 9, Folder 3, Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Electronic Records, 2003-2008; FA_MSS_564_ER_18
  - Braun-Reinitz, Janet and Jane Weissman -- On the Wall: Four Decades of Community Murals in New York City, 2002-2009
    - Correspondence, Drafts, Research Material, Press, and Grant Applications, 2002-2009 (Box 9, Folder 4-6)
    - Photographs, Prints, and Postcards, 2009 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Front and Back Covers, 2009 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Electronic Records, FA_MSS_564_ER_19
  - Unrealized Project -- Cuban Murals, 2003-2004 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Unrealized Project -- Braun-Reinitz, Janet (Project Director/Designer) -- Ousmane Zongo Memorial Mural, 2003-2005
    - Correspondence, Press, and Photographs, 2003-2005 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Electronic Records, FA_MSS_564_ER_20
  - Braun-Reinitz, Janet -- Things Fall Apart -- Co-Sponsored by Artmakers, 2004
    - Photographs and Press, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Preparatory Painting, circa 2004 (Flat-file-folder 5 left)
    - Electronic Records, FA_MSS_564_ER_21
  - Multiple Artists -- When Women Pursue Justice, 2005-2006
    - Correspondence, Press, Exhibition Catalog, and Grant Applications, 2005-2006 (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
    - Drawings, circa 2005 (Box 10, Folder 3, Box 15, Folder 16, Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Photographs, circa 2005 (Box 10, Folder 4-5)
    - Preparatory Paintings and Study, circa 2005 (Box 20, Folder 10-12)
    - Slides, circa 2005 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Mugs, circa 2005 (Box 13)
    - Togut, Susan -- "Clara Lemlich" Drawing, 2005 (Flat-file-folder 7)
    - The Women of Nostrand and Greene: When Women Pursue Justice (A Community Mural Project) -- Documentary by Dave Reinitz, 2005; FA_MSS_564_ER_31
    - Electronic Records, FA_MSS_564_ER_22
  - Dominguez, Maria -- Reflect, Connect, Move -- Co-Sponsored by Artmakers and Brooklyn Connects, 2006 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Restoration of Homage to Seurat: La Grande Jatte in Harlem -- Sponsored by Rescue Public Murals, 2006-2009
    - Grant Applications, Correspondence, and Photographs, 2006-2009 (Box 10, Folder 7, Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Electronic Records, FA_MSS_564_ER_23
  - Dominguez, Maria -- Bronx Allegory -- Co-Sponsored by Artmakers, 2007 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Images of the African Diaspora in New York City Community Murals Exhibition, 2007-2011
    - Grant Applications, Press, and Workshop Handouts, 2009-2011 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Photographs, 2007-2009 (Box 11, Folder 2-3, Box 21, Folder 2-4)
    - Posters, 2009 (Box Shared Fales 110, Folder 9)
    - Exhibition Wall Text, circa 2009 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Photographs and Wall Text on Foam Board, 2009-2011 (Box 17, Folder Unknown, Box 18, Box 19)
    - Electronic Records, FA_MSS_564_ER_24
  - Braun-Reinitz, Janet -- We Shall Overcome -- Co-Sponsored by Artmakers and the International Campaign for Justice in Bhopal, 2009 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - "Community Murals in NYC: Protest and Celebration" -- Fall 2009 Lecture Series at Humanities Institute at Stony Brook -- Poster (Box Shared Fales 110, Folder 11)
  - Asher, Ricki, Janet Braun-Reinitz, and Androneth Siunarine -- Benjamin and Nana Krah: Portraits of a Village Mural -- Co-Sponsored by Artmakers and Nka Foundation, 2010-2011 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Perrottet, Camille (Designer/Lead Artist) -- The Federico Garcia Lorca Murals, 2011-2013
    - Press and Walking Tour Program, 2011-2013 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Preparatory Drawings, 2011-2013 (Box 21, Folder 5, Box 22, Folder 8, Flat-file-folder 1)
    - Electronic Records, FA_MSS_564_ER_25
  - Unrealized Project -- Restoration of Arnold Belkin's Against Domestic Colonialism and The Legacy of Arnold Belkin: Identity, Community, and Education Exhibition, 2011-2013
    - Correspondence, Grant Applications, and Photographs, 2011-2013 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Electronic Records, FA_MSS_564_ER_26
  - Multiple Unrealized Projects, 2011-2016
    - Correspondence, 2011-2014 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Electronic Records, 2012-2016; FA_MSS_564_ER_27
  - Braun-Reinitz, Janet and Hildegund Shuster -- Women's Labor in New York City and Hamburg Harbors: Bridging the Two Ports -- Co-Sponsored by Artmakers, 2013 (Box 11, Folder 9)